https://www.pearsoncollegelondon.ac.uk/legal/data-protection-notice.html?intid=FO_CB1_6

Data protection notice
At Pearson College London, we know that you care about how your personal information is used, and we appreciate that you trust us to do so carefully and sensibly.
Pearson College London is responsible for the personal data it collects and holds and, under data protection legislation, we have a duty to inform you of the different ways in which your data is used, what information we hold and how, why we collect it and our legal basis for doing so, whether we share that data with anyone else and your rights in relation to your personal data.
This Policy sets out how PCL processes the personal data, including data passed to us by third parties, of the following:
Prospective students, including enquirers and applicants. This covers the period up to enrolment.
Current students. This means students who are enrolling and those currently registered with PCL.
Alumni. This means students who have completed a programme of study, including short courses, with PCL.
In addition to the information set out in this Policy, you may be provided with further information about the processing of your personal data when you engage with specific services or activities with us, and you may be asked to provide consent to such processing.
Pearson College Limited is registered with the Independent Commissioner’s Office under registration number Z3188453.
This Privacy notice was last updated in July 2020.
What is personal data?
Personal data is information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual. This could be information that identifies an individual on its own, such as a name or identifying photograph, or it could be information used in combination with other information to identify someone, such as a date of birth or nationality.
Prospective students
What information does Pearson College London collect?
We currently collect and process the following information on our prospective students:
Personal details such as name, contact details (address, telephone number, email address) and date of birth (age)
Education and work history, and career aspirations
Unique identifiers, for example application reference numbers
Online identifiers (for example, IP addresses and cookie identifiers). For more information please see our Cookie Policy
Proof of identity, e.g. Passport National Insurance Number
Next of kin information
Nationality Information on household income
Student finance information
Identifying photograph
We may also collect some special category data:
Race/ethnicity
Health information (including disabilities)
How does Pearson College London collect my personal information?
Most of the personal information we process is provided to us directly by you, for example, when you register for events, order publications such as a prospectus, use our website chat function or make an application for a programme.
We sometimes collect bank card details for payments made over the telephone but do not store credit/debit card details. We are PCI DSS compliant.
We may also receive personal information on you indirectly, for example:
where applications are made through UCAS
for degree apprenticeships, we may receive information from your employer
information provided by you to third-party search engines, marketing sites or registering for events via a third-party platform
information shared on peer recruitment websites, such as The Access Platform or UniBuddy
information provided by educational institutions or partners
information that is in the public domain, for example through social media sites
What does Pearson College London do with my data?
Your information will be used by marketing, recruitment and admissions staff and may be shared with other departments within the College to support this process or to improve access to services.
We may also share your data with third parties, for example:
regulatory bodies, government agencies or other organisations in order to comply with legislation and regulatory requirements;
Higher Education Access Tracker Service, to monitor the effectiveness of our outreach activities. Their Privacy Notice can be found here.
online platforms or data management system providers with whom we have a contract e.g.:
Salesforce – our customer relationship management system
SITS:Vision – our student management information system
Inzite – our online interview platform
present or potential employers, for example in the application process for degree apprenticeships
staff within Pearson plc and/or its subsidiaries where we use their services. For example, the College currently uses Pearson plc IT and finance systems
Where we use third parties to provide services on our behalf (acting as data processors), a written contract will be put in place to ensure that your information will be held in accordance with the requirements of data protection legislation. There are circumstances in which your data may be transferred outside of the EEA, e.g. where we use a third-party cloud services provider based outside the EEA to store personal data. In such cases there will be appropriate safeguards in place to protect the security of your personal information.
Parents, family members and other guardians are considered to be third parties and your information will not be disclosed to them unless you have given your consent for relevant information in certain circumstances to be shared, or we believe the disclosure is otherwise made in accordance with data protection legislation.
Purposes for processing and our lawful basis for processing your data
Your personal data will be used to manage your enquiry or prospective application to Pearson College London.
We have set out below the purposes and the legal basis upon which we process the personal data of prospective students.
Purpose
Legal Bais
Marketing and publicity
We will collect personal data from you in order to provide you with information concerning our products and services and where you have registered an interest in a promotional event, such as a taster day or open day.
We will not provide you with any marketing emails if you have not opted in to receiving them. You have the option to unsubscribe at any time.
If you attend an event at Pearson College London, we may take photographs or video to be used in marketing and publicity materials.
Legitimate interests
We will process your data in order to pursue the legitimate interests of the College, for example, in promoting and enhancing our products and services.
Pre-application queries and processing and managing applications
We will use your information to:
provide guidance on applying to the College
provide information on opportunities and support that the College can provide
assess your eligibility to study at the College
administer online tests as part of your application, where applicable
invite you to workshops
assess your application
create a student record on our Student Management Information System
shortlist candidates for interview and provide details to the interviewers
communicate with you regarding your application
In some cases, we will collect special category data, such as health information and race or ethnicity. We collect this data for the following reasons:
to assess whether reasonable adjustments may be required
to monitor access and participation
to comply with regulatory and legal requirements
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The College is required to assess your application before entering into a contract with you when you accept a place with the College.
For special category data
Equality of opportunity or treatment
We process special category data to monitor equality of opportunity or treatment.
Explicit consent
Where we collect information on health to assess whether reasonable adjustments may be required, we rely on explicit consent.
Fees and funding
We will process your personal data in order to ascertain the financial details of your contractual relationship with us.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The College may be required to process your personal data before entering into a contract with you when you accept a place with the College.
Internal reporting, statutory reporting and other legal obligations
We will process your personal data in order to:
comply with our legal obligations
produce statistics and reporting for internal and statutory reporting purposes
monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of our access and participation activities.
Compliance with a legal obligation
The College will process your personal data in order to comply with legislation, such as Health and Safety.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
For special category data
Equality of opportunity or treatment
We process special category data to monitor equality of opportunity or treatment.
Registered students
What information does Pearson College London collect about me?
We currently collect and process the following information on our enrolling and registered students:
Personal details such as name, contact details (address, telephone number, email address) and date of birth (age)
Education and work history, and career aspirations
Unique identifiers, for example Unique Learner Numbers, Student reference numbers
Online identifiers (for example, IP addresses and cookie identifiers). Please see our Cookie Policy for more information
Next of kin information
Nationality status Information on household income
Student finance information Identifying photograph
Enrolment status
We also collect some special category data:
Race or ethnicity
Health information (including disabilities)
Religious or philosophical beliefs
Sexual Orientation
How does Pearson College London collect my personal information?
Most of the personal information we process is provided to us directly by you, when you enrol with us.
We may also receive personal information on you from third parties, for example:
from government agencies, such as the Student Loans Company, or Learner Records Service
for degree apprenticeships, we may receive information from your employer
information provided by you to third party search engines, marketing sites or registering for events via a third-party platform
information that is in the public domain, for example through social media sites
What does Pearson College London do with my data?
Your information will be used by staff in different departments across the College in order to administer your education and student experience and to improve our services.
We may also share your data with third parties, for example:
Regulatory bodies, government agencies or other organisations in order to comply with legislation and regulatory requirements. The main agencies with whom we share data are:
The Higher Education Statistics Agency, the designated data body of the Office for Students. For more information about their use of your personal data, please see their Collection Notices
The Education and Skills Funding Agency, which administers funding for apprenticeships. Their privacy notice can be found here
Your contact details may be passed to the Office for Students in order to administer the National Student Survey
The Student Loans Company
The Office of the Independent Adjudicator
Higher Education Access Tracker Service, to monitor the effectiveness of our outreach activities. Their Privacy Notice can be found here
Our validating partner, the University of Kent, which awards our degrees
External examiners, as part of our quality assurance processes
Where our programme of study leads to a qualification recognised by a professional body, we will disclose data required by those bodies, e.g. Solicitors Regulation Authority, Chartered Management Institute
Online platforms or data management system providers with whom we have a contract, e.g.:
Salesforce – our customer relationship management system
SITS:Vision – our student management information system
Onefile – apprenticeship portfolio software
Turnitin – anti-plagiarism software
Blackboard – our online learning platform
Abintegro – career development software
Employers, for example apprentice employers, or to administer internship opportunities
Staff within Pearson plc and/or its subsidiaries where we use their services. For example, the College currently uses Pearson plc IT and finance systems
External auditors, where necessary to carry out their audit function
Debt collection agencies acting on our behalf where you owe us money
We may be obliged to contact third parties, such as your next of kin or emergency services in an emergency or where we have serious concerns about your wellbeing or the safety of others
Where we use third parties to provide services on our behalf (acting as data processors), a written contract will be put in place to ensure that your information will be held in accordance with the requirements of data protection legislation. There are circumstances in which your data may be transferred outside of the EEA, e.g. where we use a third-party cloud services provider based outside the EEA to store personal data. In such cases there will be appropriate safeguards in place to protect the security of your personal information.
Parents, family members and other guardians are considered to be third parties and your information will not be disclosed to them unless you have given your consent for relevant information in certain circumstances to be shared, or we believe the disclosure is otherwise made in accordance with data protection legislation.
Purposes for processing and our lawful basis for processing your data
Your personal data will be used to manage the delivery and administration of your education and student experience with Pearson College London.
We have set out below the purposes and the legal basis upon which we process the personal data of prospective students.
Purpose
Legal basis
Enrolment
We will collect personal data from you in order to enrol you as a student once you have accepted an offer of a place.
At the point of enrolment we will process special category data such as health information, race, ethnicity.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The processing of your personal data is necessary in relation to the contract you have entered into with the College.
For special category data
Equality of opportunity or treatment
We process special category data to monitor equality of opportunity or treatment.
Delivery and administration of education
We will use your information to:
Provide your education
Record your progress
Maintain your student record on our Student Management Information System
Communicate with you about your education
We may make audio or visual recordings of lectures but students will be provided with notice beforehand.
We may process personal data such as health information, for example if reasonable adjustments are required for teaching or assessment.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The processing of your personal data is necessary in relation to the contract you have entered into with the College.
For special category data
Explicit Consent
Where we collect information on health to assess whether reasonable adjustments may be required, we rely on explicit consent.
Delivery and administration of student experience
We will process your personal information in order to:
Administer quality assurance processes, such as complaints, appeals, disciplinary matters, extenuating circumstances applications, deferrals, extension requests and academic malpractice
Manage your use of facilities and services e.g. IT, online learning environment, library
Provide support from Student Services, such as administrative support, guidance on College processes and procedures
Provide access to talent development opportunities and events
Provide a counselling service
Produce your Student ID
We may process special category data, such as data relating to your health, for example where this is disclosed in an application for extenuating circumstances or to our counselling service.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The processing of your personal data is necessary in relation to the contract you have entered into with the College.
Legitimate interests
Sometimes we will process your data in order to pursue the legitimate interests of the College, for example, in promoting our events and services.
For special category data
Equality of opportunity or treatment
We process special category data to monitor equality of opportunity or treatment.
Vital interests
In the event of concerns about your wellbeing or safety, or that of others, it may be necessary to transfer your personal data to emergency services
Explicit consent
Where it is unnecessary or inappropriate to rely on vital interests, we will seek consent to the processing of your data at the point of collection.
Internal reporting, statutory reporting and other legal obligations
We will process your personal data in order to:
comply with our legal obligations
produce statistics and reporting for internal and statutory reporting purposes
monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of our access and participation activities
We will process special category personal data, e.g information about disabilities or ethnicity. We also collect information about religious views and/or sexual orientation and, where disclosed, report this information to HESA.
Compliance with a legal obligation
The College will process your personal data in order to comply with legislation, such as Health and Safety.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
For special category data
Equality of opportunity or treatment
We process special category data to monitor equality of opportunity or treatment.
Fees and funding
We will process your personal data in order to manage the financial aspects of your contractual relationship with us.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Performance of contract
The College may be required to process your personal data before entering into a contract with you when you accept a place with the College.
Alumni relations
We use your data to:
manage and facilitate graduation, including gown hire and publishing names in the programme
maintain contact preferences for alumni activities and talent development
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Legitimate interests
Sometimes we will process your data in order to pursue the legitimate interests of the College, for example, in promoting our products and services.
Consent
Where we cannot rely on performance of a task carried out in the public interest or legitimate interest for our processing of data, we will obtain your consent.
Marketing and publicity
We will process your personal data in order to provide you with information concerning our events.
We may take photographs or video to be used in marketing and publicity materials.
Legitimate interests
We will process your data in order to pursue the legitimate interests of the College, for example, in promoting our products and services.
Alumni
What information does Pearson College London collect about me?
We currently collect and process the following information on our alumni:
Personal details such as name, contact details (address, telephone number, email address) and date of birth (age)
Education and work history, and career aspirations
Unique identifiers, for example Unique Learner Numbers, Student reference numbers
Online identifiers (for example, IP addresses and cookie identifiers)
Nationality status Identifying photograph
We also process some special category data:
Health information (including disabilities)
Ethnicity
How does Pearson College London collect my personal information?
Most of the personal information we process is provided to us directly by you or will retained from your pre-existing records.
We may also receive personal information on you indirectly, for example:
information provided by you to third party search engines, marketing sites or registering for events via a third-party platform
information that is in the public domain, for example through social media sites
Your information will be used by marketing, alumni and talent development staff and may be shared with other departments within the College to support this process or to improve access to services.
We may also share your data with third parties, for example:
Regulatory bodies, government agencies or other organisations in order to comply with legislation and regulatory requirements, for example with the Higher Education Statistics Agency to facilitate Graduate Outcomes. For more information about their use of your personal data, please see their Collection Notices
Online platforms or data management system providers with whom we have a contract, e.g.:
Salesforce – our customer relationship management system
SITS:Vision – we will continue to hold information on our student management information system
Employers, for talent development opportunities or to provide referencing at your request
Staff within Pearson plc and/or its subsidiaries where we use their services. For example, the College currently uses Pearson plc IT and finance systems
External auditors, where necessary to carry out their audit function
Debt collection agencies acting on our behalf where you owe us money
Where we use third parties to provide services on our behalf (acting as data processors), a written contract will be put in place to ensure that your information will be held in accordance with the requirements of data protection legislation. There are circumstances in which your data may be transferred outside of the EEA, e.g. where we use a third-party cloud services provider based outside the EEA to store personal data. In such cases there will be appropriate safeguards in place to protect the security of your personal information.
Parents, family members and other guardians are considered to be third parties and your information will not be disclosed to them unless you have given your consent for relevant information in certain circumstances to be shared, or we believe the disclosure is otherwise made in accordance with data protection legislation.
Purposes for processing and our lawful basis for processing your data
Your personal data will be used to maintain your relationship with Pearson College London and to offer alumni services.
We have set out below the purposes and the legal basis upon which we process the personal data of alumni.
Purpose
Legal basis
Maintaining records of student's relationship with Pearson College London
We will process your data to maintain records of your relationship with Pearson College London.
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Internal reporting, statutory reporting and other legal obligations
We will process your personal data in order to:
Facilitate the Graduate Outcomes survey
produce statistics and reporting for internal and statutory reporting purposes
Performance of a task carried out in the public interest.
The College will be processing personal data in its capacity as a registered higher education provider with the Office for Students under the approved (fee cap) category.
Promoting and providing relevant events/activities
We will process data in order to:
provide information on events and activities that might be of interest
invite alumni to participate in or speak at events being held by the College
improve our events and services
We will not provide you with any marketing emails if you have not opted in to receiving them. You have the option to unsubscribe at any time.
If you attend an event at Pearson College London, we may take photographs or video to be used in marketing and publicity materials.
Legitimate interests
We will process your data in order to pursue the legitimate interests of the College, for example, in promoting and enhancing our products and services.
How long will you store my information?
We will only keep your information for as long as we need it to fulfil our purposes, including any relating to legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
Your data protection rights
Under data protection law, you have rights including:
Your right of access - You have the right to ask us for copies of your personal information.
Your right to rectification - You have the right to ask us to rectify personal information you think is inaccurate. You also have the right to ask us to complete information you think is incomplete.
Your right to erasure - You have the right to ask us to erase your personal information in certain circumstances.
Your right to restriction of processing - You have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances.
Your right to object to processing - You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances.
Your right to data portability - You have the right to ask that we transfer the personal information you gave us to another organisation, or to you, in certain circumstances.
Further information on your rights can be found on the Information Commissioner’s Office website. You are not required to pay any charge for exercising your rights. If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you.
Who can I contact with questions?
If you have any concerns or questions about our use of your personal information, you can contact us by writing to:
If we are unable to address your query or concerns to your satisfaction, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office:
The ICO’s address:
